Guide to the John Punnett Peters Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Professional Papers, 1909-1956; Series I; 2.9 linear feet (7 boxes)
  - Osgood, Robert B.
    See: box 2, folder 59
  - "P" general, 1919-1956, undated (Box 7, Folder 166)
  - Parran, Thomas, 1941-1948, undated (Box 7, Folder 167)
  - Peace Information Center, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 168)
  - Perry, Ralph Barton, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 169)
  - The Physicians Forum, Inc. (*), 1942-1955 (Box 7, Folder 170)
  - Progressive Citizens of America (*), 1947-1948 (Box 7, Folder 171)
  - Quotations, undated (Box 7, Folder 172)
  - "R" general, 1929-1955 (Box 7, Folder 173)
  - "S" general, 1923-1955, undated (Box 7, Folder 174)
  - Scharles, Frederick H., 1931 (Box 7, Folder 175)
  - Smith, George H., 1931-1937, undated (Box 7, Folder 176)
  - Smith, Richard M.
    See: box 3, folders 70-71
  - Spanish refugees (*), 1939-1941 (Box 7, Folder 177)
  - Sprunt, Douglas H., 1931-1932 (Box 7, Folder 178)
  - Starr, Isaac, Jr., 1932 (Box 7, Folder 179)
  - Stetson, Richard P. (*), 1931 (Box 7, Folder 180)
  - Stokes, John H.
    See: box 3, Folder 81
  - Swingle, W. W. (*), 1931-1932 (Box 7, Folder 181)
  - Switzer, Mary E.
  - "T" general, 1931-1951, undated (Box 7, Folder 182)
  - Thomas, Charles, C.
    See: box 13, folder 375
  - Tillett, William S.
  - "U" general, 1940-1954 (Box 7, Folder 183)
  - United States, Department of the Army (*), 1947-1955 (Box 7, Folder 184)
    See also: box 6, Folder 153, Moursund
    See also: box 7, folder 190
  - United States, Department of War (*), 1943-1947 (Box 7, Folder 185)
  - "V" general, 1931-1947 (Box 7, Folder 186)
  - Veeder, Borden S.
    See: box 3, folder 82
  - Van Slyke, Donald D., 1924-1947 (Box 7, Folder 187)
    See also: box 13, folders 376-378
  - "W" general, 1919-1955 (Box 7, Folder 188)
  - Walker, Alexander, 1931-1932 (Box 7, Folder 189)
  - Waxler, Samuel H. (*), 1948-1949 (Box 7, Folder 190)
  - Weech, A. A., 1932 (Box 7, Folder 193)
  - West, Randolph
    See: box 4, folder 115
  - Weymouth, Frank W., 1952, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 194)
  - Williams and Wilkins Company, 1933-1941 (Box 7, Folder 195)
  - Woods, Archie S.
    See: box 6, folder 146
  - "Y" general, 1944, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 196)
  - Yale University (*), 1931-1955 (Box 7, Folder 197)
  - Unidentified, 1925-1951, undated (Box 7, Folder 198)
- Writings, 1921-1961; Series II; 4.8 linear feet (12 boxes)
  Series II, WRITINGS, is divided into four sections: Articles, Speeches, Books, and Writings of Others. Articles, Speeches, and Writings of Others are arranged in chronological order, while in the section Books, the material on Body Water: The Exchange of Fluids in Man comes first, followed by typescripts and correspondence concerning Quantitative Clinical Chemistry, and lastly by writings consisting of chapters or sections of larger works.
  Correspondence related to an article, speech, or book is placed with that material. Indeed, in several folders in the Speeches section, there is correspondence concerning an upcoming address, but there is no copy of the text of the speech (see, for example, folders 343, 346, 350, 363).
  - Articles
    - "II. The Cargon Dioxide Absorption Curve and Carbon Dioxide Tension of the Blood in Cardiac Dyspriea", 1921 (Box 8, Folder 199)
    - "The Effect of Infection on Diabetes and Gilyeosuria", 1923 (Box 8, Folder 200)
    - "The Plasma Proteins in Relation to Blood Hydration, I", 1925 (Box 8, Folder 201)
    - "Total Acid-Base Equilibrium of Plasma in Health and Disease, VI", 1925 (Box 8, Folder 202)
    - "The Relation of Albuminuria to Protein Requirement in Nephritis", 1926 (Box 8, Folder 203)
    - "Total Acid-Base Equilibrium to Plasma in Health Disease, VII", 1927 (Box 8, Folder 204)
    - "The Production of Edema and Serum Protein Deficiency in White Rats by Low Protein Diets", 1929 (Box 8, Folder 205)
    - "The Plasma Proteins in Relation to Blood Hydration, IV-V", 1930 (Box 8, Folder 206)
    - "Chemistry and Physiology of Calcification", 1930 (Box 8, Folder 207)
    - "The Plasma Proteins in Relation to Blood Hydration, VI", 1931 (Box 8, Folder 208)
    - "The Plasma Proteins in Relation to Blood Hydration, VII-IX", 1932 (Box 8, Folder 209)
    - "Carbohydrate Metabolism in a Case of Hemochromatosis", 1932 (Box 8, Folder 210)
    - "The Acid-Base Equilibrium in Abnormal Pregnancy", 1932 (Box 8, Folder 211)
    - "The Alleged Alkalosis in Pregnancy", 1932 (Box 8, Folder 212)
    - "Salt and Water Metabolism in Nephritis", 1932 (Box 8, Folder 213)
    - France. Archives Nationales and Archives Départementales, 1932 (Box 8, Folder 214)
    - "Mercury Poisoning", 1933 (Box 8, Folder 215)
    - "The Nature of Diabetic Acidosis", 1933 (Box 8, Folder 216)
    - "Serum Proteins in Diabetic Acidosis", 1933 (Box 8, Folder 217)
    - "The Distribution and Movement of Water and Solutes in the Human Body", 1933 (Box 8, Folder 218)
    - "The Nature of 'preformed Water'", 1933 (Box 8, Folder 219)
    - "A Note on the Calculation of Water Exchange", 1933 (Box 8, Folder 220)
    - "Gravimetric Determination of Serum Cholesterol Adapted to the Man and Gildea Fatty Acid Method, with a Note on the Estimation of Lipoid Phosphorus", 1933 (Box 8, Folder 221)
    - "Permeability of Capillaries to Plasma Lipoids", 1933 (Box 8, Folder 222)
    - "The Serum Proteins in Diseases Not Primarily Affecting the Cardiovascular System or Kidneys", 1933 (Box 8, Folder 223)
    - "Lipoids of Serum in Diabetic Acidosis", 1934 (Box 8, Folder 224)
    - "A Critical Estimate of the Value of Laboratory Procedures in Disorders of Metabolism", 1934 (Box 8, Folder 225)
    - "Lipoid-Chlorine in Serum", 1934 (Box 8, Folder 226)
    - "Serum Lipoids in Diabetes", 1935 (Box 8, Folder 227)
    - "Some Factors in the Etiology of Bright's Disease", 1935 (Box 8, Folder 228)
    - "The Clinical Value of Blood Chemistry", 1935 (Box 8, Folder 229)
    - "Osmotic Exchanges in Blood (A Preliminary Report)", 1936 (Box 8, Folder 230)
    - "Pyelitis in Toxemias of Pregnancy", 1936 (Box 8, Folder 231)
    - Clinical Applications of Biochemistry", 1936 (Box 8, Folder 232)
    - "The Role of Pyelitis in the Production of Toxemias of Pregnancy", 1936 (Box 8, Folder 233)
    - "The Nature of Eelampsia", 1937 (Box 8, Folder 234)
    - "Improvement of Medical Care", 1937 (Box 8, Folder 235)
    - "Pathology of Pregnancy Toxemias", 1937 (Box 8, Folder 236)
    - "Still More on 'Principles and Proposals'", 1937 (Box 8, Folder 237)
    - "The Nature of the Toxemias of Pregnancy", 1938 (Box 8, Folder 238)
    - "Individualized Treatment of Diabetes", 1938 (Box 8, Folder 239)
    - "Transfers of Water and Solutes in the Body", 1938 (Box 8, Folder 240)
    - "The Principles and Proposals for the Improvement of Medical Care", 1938 (Box 8, Folder 241)
    - "The Future of American Medicine: Our Problems and Possible Solutions", 1938 (Box 8, Folder 242)
    - "Public Health: A Challenge," statement by John P. Peters, 1938 (Box 8, Folder 243)
    - "Medicine and the Public", 1939 (Box 8, Folder 244-245)
    - "Metabolic Disorders in Gastrointestinal Diseases", 1939 (Box 8, Folder 246)
    - "Serum Lipoids and Proteins in Hypothyroidism", 1939 (Box 9, Folder 247)
    - "Free Experimentation in Meeting Medical Needs: A Professional View", 1939 (Box 9, Folder 248)
    - "The Quality of Medical Care under Public Auspices", 1939 (Box 9, Folder 249)
    - "Serum Lipoids and Proteins in Hypothyroidism", 1940 (Box 9, Folder 250)
    - "Differential Diagnosis of Basophilism and Allied Conditions", 1940 (Box 9, Folder 251)
    - "The Structure of the Blood in Relation to Surgical Problems", 1940 (Box 9, Folder 252)
    - "Some Reactions by Which Solutes May Be Differentially Concentrated by the Kidney", 1940 (Box 9, Folder 253)
    - "Blood Iodine in Patients with Thyroid Disease", 1941 (Box 9, Folder 254)
    - "Electrolyte Balances in Obstruction of the Gastrointestinal Tract", 1941 (Box 9, Folder 255)
    - "The Social Implications of Medical Science", 1942 (Box 9, Folder 256)
    - "Water Metabolism", 1942 (Box 9, Folder 257)
    - "Medical Education in Wartime", 1943 (Box 9, Folder 258)
    - "The Interrelation of Serum Lipids in Normal Persons", 1943 (Box 9, Folder 259)
    - "Blood Ketones and Serum Lipids in Starvation and Water Deprivation", 1944 (Box 9, Folder 260)
    - "Problems of Nitrogen Metabolism", 1944 (Box 9, Folder 261)
    - "Water Exchange", 1944 (Box 9, Folder 262)
    - "The Effect of Starvation on Diabetes Insipidus", 1944 (Box 9, Folder 263)
    - "Starvation Diabetes, the Reason for the Use of Glucose in the Treatment of Diabetic Acidosis", 1945 (Box 9, Folder 264)
    - "The Need for a National Health Program", 1946 (Box 9, Folder 265)
    - "Plasma a-Amino Acid Nitrogen and Serum Lipds of Surgical Patients", 1946 (Box 9, Folder 266)
    - "Nitrogen Metabolism in Acute and Chronic Disease", 1946 (Box 9, Folder 267)
    - "Some Metabolic Reactions to Injury", 1946 (Box 9, Folder 268)
    - "The Distribution and Movements of Carbon Dioxide between Cells and Serum of Oxygenated Human Blood", 1947 (Box 9, Folder 269)
    - "Alexander Woodward Winkler", 1947 (Box 9, Folder 270)
    - "The Significance of Serum Sodium", 1949 (Box 9, Folder 271)
    - "Diagnostic Significance of Electrolyte Disturbances", 1949 (Box 9, Folder 272)
    - "Serum Precipitable Iodine in Patients with Tumors of or Near the Pituitary", 1949 (Box 9, Folder 273)
    - "Toxic Effects of Antithyroid Drugs", 1949 (Box 9, Folder 274)
    - "Artifactual Values of Serum Precipitate Iodine", 1950 (Box 9, Folder 275)
    - "Malnutrition and Edema", 1950 (Box 9, Folder 276)
    - "Sodium Water and Edema", 1950 (Box 9, Folder 277)
    - "A Salt-Wasting Syndrome Associated with Cerebral Disease", 1950 (Box 9, Folder 278)
    - "The Preceipitable Iodine Serum in Pregnancy Complicated by Disorders of the Thyroid", 1951 (Box 9, Folder 279)
    - "The Lipids of Serum in Pregnancy", 1951 (Box 9, Folder 280)
    - "The Interrelationship of Foodstuffs in Metabolism", 1951 (Box 9, Folder 281)
    - "Acute Renal Failure" Lower Nephron Nephrosis", 1951 (Box 9, Folder 282)
    - "Laboratory Aids to Diagnosis and Therapy", 1951 (Box 9, Folder 283)
    - "The Problem of Cardiac Edema", 1952 (Box 9, Folder 284)
    - "Diabetic Acidosis", 1952 (Box 9, Folder 285)
    - "The Application of Modern Chemistry to Medicine", 1952 (Box 9, Folder 286)
    - "Lower Nephron Nephrosis", 1952 (Box 9, Folder 287)
    - "The Nature and Formation of Thoracic Duct Chyle", 1953 (Box 9, Folder 288)
    - "Edema of Acute Nephritis", 1953 (Box 9, Folder 289)
    - "Physiology of Renal Excretion of Potassium", 1953 (Box 9, Folder 290)
    - "Carl Schmidt, 1823-1894," article draft, undated (Box 9, Folder 291)
  - Speeches
    - Re: Committee of Physicians' Principles and Proposals, 1938 (Box 10, Folder 292-293)
    - "The Dilemma of Medicine", 1938 (Box 10, Folder 294)
    - "The Social Responsibilities of Medicine", 1938 (Box 10, Folder 295)
    - Re: medical care, 1938 (Box 10, Folder 296)
    - Re: health insurance, 1938 (Box 10, Folder 297)
    - "Report on the Conference on Health Insurance", 1938 (Box 10, Folder 298)
    - Re: health insurance, 1938 (Box 10, Folder 299)
    - Re: hospitals and medical care, 1938 (Box 10, Folder 300)
    - Re: National Health Conference, 1938 (Box 10, Folder 301)
    - Re: health insurance, 1938 (Box 10, Folder 302-303)
    - "The Responsibility of a Physician Towards a Health Program", 1939 (Box 10, Folder 304)
    - "Changing Values in Medicine", 1939 (Box 10, Folder 305)
    - Radio broadcast re: socialized medicine, 1939 (Box 10, Folder 306)
    - "Good Medicine for the Public", 1939 (Box 10, Folder 307)
    - Testimony on Wagner Bill (S 1620), 1939 (Box 10, Folder 308)
    - Re: Wagner Bill (S 1620), 1939 (Box 10, Folder 309)
    - "Exchanges of Water and Solutes", 1939 (Box 10, Folder 310)
    - "The Quality of Medical Care under Public Auspices", 1939 (Box 10, Folder 311)
    - "Practicing Medicine for Service", 1939 (Box 10, Folder 312)
    - "Social Implications of Medical Science", 1939 (Box 10, Folder 313)
    - "The Reorientation of Medicine", 1940 (Box 10, Folder 314)
    - "A National Health Program", 1940 (Box 10, Folder 315)
    - "Exchanges of Fluids and Solutes in the Body and Between the Body and its Environment", 1940 (Box 10, Folder 316)
    - Re: Committee of Physicians for the Improvement of Medical Care, 1940 (Box 10, Folder 317)
    - "The Scientist and Social Problems: Public Health", 1940 (Box 10, Folder 318)
    - "Social Responsiblities of Physicians", 1942 (Box 10, Folder 319)
    - "The Effect of the War on the Quality of Medical Care", 1943 (Box 10, Folder 320)
    - "Medical Education in Wartime", 1943 (Box 10, Folder 321)
    - "Should Medicine Be Merely Derivative?", 1943 (Box 10, Folder 322)
    - "Recent Advances in Nutrition and Metabolism", 1944 (Box 10, Folder 323)
    - "Planning for Post War Medicine", 1944 (Box 10, Folder 324)
    - Statement before Senate Subcommittee on wartime health and education, 1944 (Box 10, Folder 325)
    - "A Program for Better Health: Facilities. The Professional Staff. Who Pays the Bills?", 1944 (Box 10, Folder 326)
    - "Medical Care for Veterans and Civilians", 1944 (Box 10, Folder 327)
    - "Should We Adopt Government Health Insurance?", 1944 (Box 10, Folder 328)
    - "Independent Voters Committee of the Arts and Sciences", 1944 (Box 10, Folder 329)
    - Anuria cases—Shock cases, 1945 (Box 11, Folder 330)
    - Re: National Health Program, 1946 (Box 11, Folder 331-332)
    - Script for "The National Hour," NBC radio, 1946 (Box 11, Folder 333)
    - Re: National Health Program, 1946 (Box 11, Folder 334-335)
    - "The Need for a Comprehensive National Health Program", 1946 (Box 11, Folder 336)
    - Re: National Health Program, 1947 (Box 11, Folder 337)
    - Re: quality of medical services, 1947 (Box 11, Folder 338)
    - Statement before Senate Committee on Education and Labor, 1947 (Box 11, Folder 339)
    - Re: "The Role of Sodium in the Production of Edema", 1947-1948 (Box 11, Folder 340)
    - "Why Doctors Need a National Health Program", 1948 (Box 11, Folder 341)
    - Re: water balance, 1948-1949 (Box 11, Folder 342)
    - Re: water metabolism, 1948-1949 (Box 11, Folder 343)
    - Re: sodium and potassium, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 344)
    - Re: clinical aspects of fluid administration, 1948-1949 (Box 11, Folder 345)
    - Re: panel discussion on protein hydrolysates in nutrition, 1948-1949 (Box 11, Folder 346)
    - "The Need for a National Health Program", 1948 (Box 11, Folder 347)
    - Re: carbohydrate metabolism, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 348)
    - Re: lipid metabolism, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 349)
    - "Clinical Management of the Diabetic", 1948 (Box 11, Folder 350)
    - Re: water metabolism, 1949 (Box 11, Folder 351)
    - "Control of the Excretion of Salt and Water", 1949 (Box 11, Folder 352)
    - "Causes and Treatment of Lower Nephron Nephrosis", 1949 (Box 11, Folder 353)
    - Re: health insurance, 1949 (Box 11, Folder 354)
    - Re: body water and its relation to surgery and anesthesiology, 1949 (Box 11, Folder 355)
    - "The Causes and Instance of Salt Deficiency", 1949 (Box 11, Folder 356)
    - "The Incidence and Correction of Some Electrolyte Disturbances in Clinical Medicine", 1950 (Box 11, Folder 357)
    - Re: lower nephron nephrosis, 1950 (Box 11, Folder 358)
    - "A Salt-Washing Syndrome Associated with Cerebral Disease", 1950 (Box 11, Folder 359)
    - "Mechanics of Cardiac Failure", 1950 (Box 11, Folder 360)
    - Re: fluids in the body, 1951 (Box 11, Folder 361)
    - Re: edema, 1951 (Box 11, Folder 362)
    - Re: diabetic acidosis, 1954 (Box 11, Folder 363)
    - List of lectures by John P. Peters, 1953-1954 (Box 11, Folder 364)
  - Books
    - Body Water: The Exchange of Fluids in Man, pp. 1-700, Circa 1935 (Box 12, Folder 365-371)
    - Body Water: The Exchange of Fluids in Man, pp. 701-792, Circa 1935 (Box 13, Folder 372)
    - Body Water: The Exchange of Fluids in Man: correspondence and reviews, 1934-1942, 1962 (Box 13, Folder 373-374)
    - Body Water: The Exchange of Fluids in Man: memorabilia, 1935-1936 (Box 13, Folder 375)
    - Quantitative Clinical Chemistry: correspondence re first edition, 1931-1940 (Box 13, Folder 376-378)
    - Quantitative Clinical Chemistry: chapter drafts for second edition, Circa 1941-1946 (Box 13, Folder 379-381)
    - Quantitative Clinical Chemistry: chapter drafts for second edition, Circa1941-1946 (Box 14, Folder 382-395)
    - Quantitative Clinical Chemistry: chapter drafts for second edition, Circa 1941-1946 (Box 15, Folder 396-405)
    - Quantitative Clinical Chemistry: correspondence re second edition, 1946-1947 (Box 15, Folder 406)
    - Quantitative Clinical Chemistry: reviews of second edition, 1946-1947,1957 (Box 15, Folder 407)
    - Quantitative Clinical Chemistry, second edition, pp. 1-780., Circa1946 (Box 16, Folder 408-414)
    - Quantitative Clinical Chemistry, second edition, pp. 781-1409 and index, Circa 1946 (Box 17, Folder 415-419)
    - Re: thiourea studies, 1948 (Box 18, Folder 420)
    - "Differentiation and Specialization of Biologic Media", 1950 (Box 18, Folder 421)
    - "Water Balance in Health and Disease", 1950-1952, 1961 (Box 18, Folder 422)
    - "Serum Cholesterol and Serum Precipitable Iodine", 1952-1955 (Box 18, Folder 423)
    - "Carbohydrate Metabolism" and "Protein Metabolism", 1954-1957 (Box 18, Folder 424)
    - "Photometry", undated (Box 18, Folder 425)
  - Writings of Others
    - World War I era, 1914-1919, undated (Box 18, Folder 426)
    - A Physio-Chemical Introduction to General Chemistry, 1930 (Box 18, Folder 427)
    - Re: national health insurance, 1936-1939, undated (Box 19, Folder 428)
    - "Does America Need Compulsory Health Insurance?", 1940 (Box 19, Folder 429)
    - Speaking of Peace, 1949 (Box 19, Folder 430)
    - "The Relation of Lean Body Weight to Metabolism and Some Consequent Systemizations" by Alfred R. Behnke, 1953 (Box 19, Folder 431)
    - "The Synthesis of the Art and Science of Medicine" by H. E. Rawlinson, 1956 (Box 19, Folder 432)
- Personal Papers, 1914-1973; Series III; 0.8 linear feet (2 boxes)
  The material in Series III is arranged alphabetically by person or subject and then chronologically.
  - Correspondence, 1931-1973, undated (Box 20, Folder 433-445)
  - Drill Regulations and Service Manual for Sanitary Troops United States Army, 1914 (Box 20, Folder 446)
  - Irwin, Alice Peters, 1920-1956, undated (Box 20, Folder 447)
  - Peters, Charlotte Hodge, 1930-1946, undated (Box 20, Folder 448)
  - Peters, John Punnett (1852-1921): address and obituaries, 1913, 1922 (Box 20, Folder 449)
  - Peters, John P.
    - Bibliography, 1916-1955 (Box 20, Folder 450)
    - Biographical, 1924-1954, undated (Box 20, Folder 451)
    - Celebrations and parties, 1949-1950, n d. (Box 20, Folder 452)
    - Certificates and memberships, 1917-1955, undated (Box 20, Folder 453)
    - Curricula vitae, 1940, undated (Box 20, Folder 454)
    - Fiftieth birthday, 1937 (Box 20, Folder 455)
    - Fiftieth birthday scrapbook, 1937 (Box 21, Folder 456)
    - Government consulting, 1948-1950 (Box 21, Folder 457)
    - Memorial issue of The Yale Journal of Biology & Medicine, 1956 December (Box 21, Folder 458)
    - Military record, 1917-1921 (Box 21, Folder 459)
    - Miscellaneous, 1973, undated (Box 21, Folder 460)
    - Sixtieth birthday, 1947-1948 (Box 21, Folder 461)
    - Obituaries, 1956-1958 (Box 21, Folder 462-464)
    - Photographs, 1919-1950 (Box 21, Folder 465)
    - Translations from German, undated (Box 21, Folder 466-467)
  - Photographs, other, 1954, undated (Box 21, Folder 468)
  - Works of Joseph Priestly, 1733-1804: Preliminary Short Title List by John F. Fulton and Charlotte H. Peters, 1937-1942, 1957, undated (Box 21, Folder 469)
- Case Files, 1922-1952; Series IV; 1.5 linear feet (4 boxes)
  Series IV, CASE FILES, consists of two boxes of medical case files of diabetes patients and two boxes of files for patients with other diseases. The diabetes and other disease files are each arranged by letter.
  These records are closed until 2025.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Series IV, Case Files, is closed until January 1, 2025.
  - Diabetes patients, 1922-1952 (Box 23, Box 22, Folder 470-495)
  - Regions--general, 1922-1952 (Box 25, Box 24, Folder 496-511)
- Additional Material, 1942-1948, 1954-1957, undated; Accession 1986-M-091; 0.25; (1 box)
  Addition inventory by Carol King, 1991 Apr
  - Correspondence
    - Peters, John Punnett, 1942-1948, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Peters, John H. and Peters, Richard M., 1954-1957, undated (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
    - Correspondence pertaining to petition sent to Eisenhower re: changes in the Loyalty Security Program, 1955-1956 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Writings
    - Untitled manuscript carbon pertaining to water, undated (Box 1, Folder 5-7)
    - Untitled manuscript pertaining to osmotic pressure of cells, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - "Total Base and Electrolyte Equilibrium", [1943 or 1944?] (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Bibliography of articles and unpublished addresses of John Punnett Peters, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Book publishing agreement, 1945 July 10 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Obituary of John Punnett Peters, Alumni Bulletin, School of Medicine, 1956 January (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Additional Material, Accession 1986-M-112
  Compiled by William E. Brown, Jr., John Espy, and Robert Richards.
  - Irwin, Alice Peters, 1956 (Box 26, Folder 512)
  - Peters, Ann Wilson
    - Peters, Charlott Morse, 1949-1953 (Box 26, Folder 513-515)
    - Peters, John Punnett, 1946-1955 (Box 26, Folder 516)
  - Peters, Charlotte Morse
    - Peters, Richard Morse, 1945-1953 (Box 26, Folder 517)
    - Miscellanea, 1945-1957 (Box 26, Folder 518)
  - Peters, John Hodge, 1951, 1955 (Box 26, Folder 519)
  - Peters, John Punnett
    - Peters, Richard Morse, 1941-1955, undated (Box 26, Folder 520-528)
    - Peters, Richard Morse, 1951-1955, undated (Box 27, Folder 529-536)
    - Miscellanea, 1947-1954, undated (Box 27, Folder 537)
    - Papers concerning "loyalty" case, 1953-1954 (Box 27, Folder 538)
    - Writings, 1948-1954 (Box 27, Folder 539-546)
    - Writings, undated (Box 28, Folder 547-548)
  - Peters, Richard Morse
    - Peters, Charlotte Morse (Hodge), 1941-1955, undated (Box 29, Folder 549-557)
    - Peters, John Punnett, 1941-1955 (Box 29, Folder 558-561)
    - Miscellanea, 1945-1955 (Box 29, Folder 562)
- Additional Material, 1889, 1915-1981, undated; Accession 1991-M-035; 1.50 linear feet (4 boxes)
  Addition inventory by Carol King, 1991 Feb.
  Received from: Alice Peters Irwin, 1990 Oct 30 (1991-M-35)
  Received from: Richard M. Peters, 1991 Jan 18 (1991-M-54), 1991 Mar 1 (1991-M-62)
  - Peters, John Punnett
    - Correspondence/general files
      - General, 1950, 1955, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Peters, Charlotte Hodge (wife), [1932] (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Irwin, Alice Peters (daughter), 1938-1954 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Letters, 1947-1948, J.J.P.; bound volume of correspondence, newspaper clippings, and a photograph, 1947-1952 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Response to disloyalty charges, 1953, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Legal documents, 1915, 1919, 1954-1955, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - The Century Association Year-Book, containing memoriam to J.P.P. (correspondence laid in), 1956 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - "John P. Peters, 1887-1955," by Max Miller: Diabetes, vol.6, no.1, 1957 January-February (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Writings
      - Gasometrische Methoden Zur Analyse von Blut and anderen Lösungen, von John P. Peters and Donald D. Van Slyke, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Quantitative Clinical Chemistry: Interpretations, by John P. Peters and Donald D. Van Slyke (copy of corrected page proofs of vols. I, II), 1930-1931 (Box 1, Folder 10)